Hussein Dossoki

Technical Team Leader | Angular | .Net | Rust | Vue

Address Maadi, Cairo Egypt

Phone + (20)1019159919

E-mail husseindossoki@gmail.com

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/HusseinDossoki

WWW https://github.com/HusseinDossoki

Well-qualified Full Stack Developer familiar with wide range of programming utilities and languages. Knowledgeable of backend and frontend development requirements. Handles any part of process with ease. Collaborative team player with excellent technical abilities offering 6 years of related experience.



Work History

Jan 2018 – Senior Full Stack Web Developer

Jun 2023 FortTeck, Maadi

- Reviewed code, debugged problems, and corrected issues.
- Used .Net Core, SQL Server, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Angular
- Analyzed existing software implementations to identify areas requiring improvement.
- Collected, defined and translated user requirements into project designs and implementation plans.
- Providing technical leadership, including mentoring on software engineering design, development, and frameworks, analysis of alternatives.

Jun 2023 - Technical Team Leader

Current Tahaluf Al Emarat, Remote

- Team Management: Overseeing the development team, including task assignment, scheduling, and performance evaluation.
- Reviewed code, debugged problems, and corrected issues.
- Used .Net Core, PostgreSQL, Angular
- Collected, defined and translated user requirements into project designs and implementation plans.
- Providing technical leadership, including mentoring on software engineering design, development, and frameworks, analysis of alternatives.



Work Experience

♦ Th

This is a list of the most important technical points in which I have practical experience:-

C# / ASP.NET Core

- Building web APIs using different design patterns (Domain Driven Design, Repository Pattern, Factory Pattern)
- CQRS and the Mediator pattern
- Implement Logging with Elasticsearch, Kibana and Serilog
- Using (ASP.NET Identity and Identity Server 4) for authentication and authorization
- Dynamically adding new roles with permissions in using only ASP.NET Identity
- Using SignalR to broadcast messages to a real time web application
- Implement caching using Redis
- Using MassTransit with RabbitMQ
- Using FluentValidation to validate incoming models
- Using Mapster and AutoMapper libraries that maps one object type to a different object type
- Performed unit and integration testing of web applications and troubleshot issues.

Databases

- Using EF core for SQL Server and PostgreSQL | Eager, Explicit and Lazy loading
- Using MongoDB driver for .Net Core application
- Implementing Database-First approach using SQL server using (stored procedures, functions, indexes)
- Using Dapper for .Net Core
- Using Firebase/Firestore with Angular/NodeJS application

DevOps

- Define and manage Azure DevOps Build and Release pipelines using YAML and GUI
- Deploy applications to Azure, a virtual machine, Docker containers, and more
- Install and configure Kubernetes on ubuntu to host my company applications

Integrations & 3rd Parties

- Implement (Stripe, Paypal, PlugnPay) Payments in ASP.NET Core & Angular
- Using QuickBooks Online APIs
- Using Twilio to send SMS Messages, SMS Verification, and SMS Notifications
- Integrating with WhatsApp APIs using (Native APIs and Twilio) to build a chatbot application

Rust

- Making HTTP Requests, and consuming Azure and GitHub APIs
- Concurrency, Spawn child threads, pass data between threads
- Dealing with Rust filesystem
- Using Tauri framework for building tiny, blazing fast binaries for all major desktop platforms
- Using actix-web and rocket frameworks to build powerful, and extremely fast web APIs



Open Source Projects

4K Video Downloader Clone https://github.com/HusseinDossoki/4k-video-downloader-clone

Dec 2022 - Present

A Clone of 4K Video Downloader written in Rust with Tauri, themed to look exactly like 4K Video Downloader, with complex features like download speed, download playlists, smart mode, etc.

• Git Mirror https://github.com/HusseinDossoki/git-mirror

Dec 2022 - Present

Git Mirror is a tool to keep multiple git repositories in sync. Whenever something is pushed to any repository, You can use this tool to forward the commits to all the others. Or you can use it to copy (Mirroring a repository in another location)

• Rust Clean Build https://aithub.com/HusseinDossoki/rust-clean-build

Dec 2022 - Present

A console application is written in Rust to build a rust app with clean build



Education

Sep 2015 - Bachelor of Computer Science: Computer Science

Jan 2020 Faculty of Computers And Information - Minya Egypt

Sep 2012 - High School Diploma

Jul 2015 Secondary School For Boys - Minya, Egypt

• Grade [92.78%]



Certifications

Jul 2017 Cloud Application Developer, IBM

Sep 2017 IBM Blockchain Essential, IBM



Additional Information

Gender: Male

Nationality: Egyptian
Birthday: 19th Jan 1997
Marital Status: Married
Military Service: Exempted